Guide to the Cedric J. Robinson and Elizabeth P. Robinson Collection on Third World News Review TAM.835
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Third World News Review Episodes, 1981-2015; 1.67 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and a cassette box; 1.79 Terabytes in 496 computer files; 3 U-matic; 15 VHS; 29 audiocassettes
  - May 16, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_322
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Dominique Strauss-Kahn being charged with attacking a New York City hotel maid, a discussion of Strauss-Kahn's career, and other sexual assault allegations against him; Michel Martelly sworn in as president of Haiti; the upcoming inauguration celebration of Alassane Ouattara in Ivory Coast; and demonstrations for Nakba Day turning violent.
  - May 23, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_323
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guest was Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the Yemeni revolution; the Sudanese government bombing villages in a new border war with South Sudan; the inauguration of Alassane Ouattara in Ivory Coast; France's political relationship with Sub-Saharan Africa; Catherine Ashton opening an EU office in Benghazi; the Libyan Civil War; the arrest of Dominique Strauss-Kahn and the impact of his arrest on the International Monetary Fund; fear of growing debt in Europe and the increased number of refugees from Africa; and the Syrian Civil War.
  - June 28, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_324
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the exit of Mohamed Abdullahi Mohamed as prime minister of Somalia and instability in the country; President Thabo Mbeki mediating negotiations between Northern and Southern Sudan; disputes over the South China Sea; the celebration of Philippine Independence Day from Spain and the 150th birthday of José Rizal; the trial of Tunisian president Zine El Abidine Ben Ali and his wife for theft; billions in missing money in Iraq; backlash against Syrian president Bashar al-Assad; and the Libyan Civil War.
  - July 11, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_325
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the death of Clyde Woods; the establishment of the Republic of South Sudan and history of Sudan; Rupert Murdoch and News of the World phone tapping scandal; Christine Lagarde being named the new head of the International Monetary Fund; the scandal surrounding Dominique Strauss-Kahn; protesters in Senegal urging President Wade to step down; the UN urging Senegal to stop the extradition of President Hissène Habré to Chad; hunger strikes in California prisons; and the role of the International Criminal Court, current cases against African heads of state, and potential upcoming cases against Libya, Syria, and Israel.
  - July 18, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_326
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Libyan Civil War and the 1969 Libyan revolution; France's decision to increase pensions for African war veterans; the Refugee Law Project in Uganda; the growing use of sexual violence as a tool of war in Uganda; and President Nelson Mandela's 90th birthday.
  - July 25, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_327
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Mahader Tesfai (Africa) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include a domestic terrorist attack in Norway; hunger strikes in California prisons; the treatment of female prisoners in Palestine and Sri Lanka; the Somali Civil War; and major drought and famine in the Horn of Africa.
  - August 8, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_328
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the 66th Anniversary of the Hiroshima atomic bomb; riots in London following the killing of Mark Duggan; a former Hungarian Nazi, Sandor Kepiro, acquitted of participating in a 1942 massacre; fighting in North Kosovo; fighting in Syria and rebellion against President Bashar al-Assad; and Israeli social justice protests.
  - August 14, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_329
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the Libyan Civil War and the assassination of Abdul Fatah Younis; the trial of President Hosni Mubarak; the growing numbers of Somali refugees in Kenya and growing number of cholera cases in refugee camps; riots in London following the killing of Mark Duggan; a State of the Nation address by President Aquino of the Philippines; and revelations that the 2004 and 2007 Filipino elections were rigged to ensure Gloria Macapagal Arroyo's victory.
  - August 29, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_330
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Mahader Tesfai (Africa) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Libyan Civil War, the end of Muammar Gaddafi's regime in Libya, and the Gaddafi family escaping to Algeria; a major drought and famine in the Horn of Africa; Eritrea planting bombs at an African Union summit in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia; the growing number of refugees leaving Africa; a suicide bomb attack against a UN building in Abuja, Nigeria by Boko Haram; and attempts at cleaning oil spills in the Niger Delta.
  - September 19, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_331
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Mahader Tesfai (Africa) and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the role of international nations in the Libyan Civil War; Libya postponing the formation of new government and the Obama doctrine; WikiLeaks revealing that major Zimbabwean military and political officials passed intelligence to U.S. embassy staff; the Dominique Strauss-Kahn scandal; Leila Lopes of Angola crowned Miss Universe; upcoming parliamentary elections in Guinea; Madagascar edging closer to a peace deal between rival factions; Laurent Gbagbo officially charged by an Ivory Coast tribunal of economic crimes; and a pipeline explosion that killed dozens in a Nairobi neighborhood.
  - September 26, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_332
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the death of Wangari Maathai; WikiLeaks and the release of Zimbabwean diplomatic cables discussing plans with the U.S. to replace President Robert Mugabe; Muslim sectarianism in Kashmir; the abuse of military power in Egypt since President Hosni Mubarak was overthrown; women gaining the right to vote in Saudi Arabia; violence during the Bahraini parliamentary by-elections; the trial of the Irvine 11; Oh Se-hoon resigning as mayor of Seoul, South Korea; and the Open Government Partnership meeting in New York City.
  - October 3, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_333
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include France rejecting Rwanda's request to extradite Agathe Habyarimana for her role in the Rwandan genocide; the assassination of Anwar al-Awlaki; the continued murders of protesters in Yemen by the government; the incarceration of Bahrain doctors for treating injured protesters; the Syrian government continuing to arrest and allegedly torture protesters; and the Chilean Winter protests.
  - October 10, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_334
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Maspero demonstrations in Cairo; the Egyptian revolution; Ellen Johnson Sirleaf, Leymah Gbowee and Tawakkol Karman being awarded the Nobel Peace Prize; controversy surrounding Liberian president Ellen Johnson Sirleaf winning the Nobel Peace Prize; upcoming Liberian elections; Ivory Coast establishing a Truth and Reconciliation Commission; a suicide bombing in Mogadishu by Al-Shabaab; and a UN report revealing Afghanistan officials had tortured detainees.
  - October 17, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_335
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Mahader Tesfai (Africa) and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the former Argentine naval officer Alfredo Astiz on trial for crimes against humanity; former Argentine Dictator Jorge Rafael Videla on trial for kidnapping children during the "Dirty War"; Victoria Montenegro revealing Lt. Col. Hernán Tetzlaff murdered her parents and kidnapped her as a child; the Uruguay River pulp mill dispute; the UN threatening Eritrea with sanctions; al-Shabaab threatening to attack Kenya due to the military's intervention in Somalia; the election in Liberia; and Occupy Wall Street.
  - October 24, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_336
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the death of Muammar Gaddafi; the history of Libyan politics; the 39th anniversary of martial law in the Philippines and the legacy of President Ferdinand Marcos; and the Kenyan army entering Somalia with the intention of fighting Al-Shabaab.
  - November 7, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_337
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guest was Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the history of secret detention center Escuela Superior de Mecánica de la Armada (ESMA) in Argentina; the Argentine general elections and re-election of Cristina Fernández de Kirchner; Argentina's debt crisis and the creation of the "empresas recuperadas" or a worker-recovered enterprise movement; Iran's nuclear weapons program; protests in Bolivia against road being built through tribal lands; and the trials of high ranking military officials from Argentina's "Dirty War."
  - November 14, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_338
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the death of Sarkis Soghanalian; the 50th Anniversary of KCSB, history of TWNR, and what led to the creation of the show; Nigerian author Chinua Achebe refusing a Nigerian national honor; and the controversial Liberian election being met with boycotts and violence, as well as the re-election of President Ellen Johnson Sirleaf.
  - November 21, 2011, TW_TAM_835_ER_339
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) and Iran's nuclear weapons program; the controversial run-off Liberian election and re-election of President Ellen Johnson Sirleaf; Kenyan and Ethiopian armies entering Somalia with the intention of fighting Al-Shabaab; economic problems in Europe; the upcoming French elections; Pope Benedict XVI's visit to Benin; Garry Conille becoming the new prime minister of Haiti; and Egypt's government offering to resign as protests grow before elections.
  - January 23, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_340
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Boston Globe's investigation into the corruption of former Liberian president President Charles Taylor; the trial of the Ocampo Six; Boko Haram's attack on Kano, Nigeria; questions about where international aid for Haiti went post-earthquake; Haitian government corruption; Senegalese singer Youssou N'Dour joining the presidential election; the end of Iraq War; the Syrian Civil War; the assassination of Iranian nuclear scientist Mostafa Ahmadi Roshan; and the 10 year anniversary of Guantanamo Bay's opening.
  - January 30, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_341
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include sanctions against Iran related to its nuclear arms program; growing tensions between Israel and Iran; the upcoming Senegalese presidential election and growing protests against Abdoulaye Wade; France's intervention with Ivory Coast elections; the trial of Laurent Gbagbo; investigations into the assassinations of Juvénal Habyarimana and Cyprien Ntaryamira; and the Rwandan genocide.
  - February 27, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_342
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Falkland Islands sovereignty dispute and 30th anniversary of Falklands War; the trial of Spanish judge Baltasar Garzón; the death of more than 300 prisoners in a Honduran prison fire; Israel agreeing to release Palestinian activist Khader Adnan from prison; allegations that the British government suppressed evidence relating to the Lockerbie bombing/Pan Am Flight 103; an agreement with BP to extract oil from Somalia; former Governor of Delta State James Ibori pleading guilty to fraud and money-laundering charges; and the 88th birthday of President Robert Mugabe.
  - March 5, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_343
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the upcoming Senegalese and French elections; the trial of former Guatemalan president Efraín Ríos Montt for crimes against humanity; the government of El Salvador apologizing for the El Mozote massacre; and the White House financing NYPD's surveillance of American Muslims.
  - March 12, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_344
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Kandahar massacre and the growing number of civilian casualties in Afghanistan; hunger strike of Palestinian activist Hana Shalabi; the documentary KONY 2012 by Invisible Children Inc. and Ugandan warlord Joseph Kony; and the School of the Americas and School of the Americas Watch.
  - March 19, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_345
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Kandahar massacre in Afghanistan; the aftermath of NATO intervention in Libya; the "ships of shame" carrying weapons from the U.S. to Egypt; the hunger strike of Palestinian activist Hana Shalabi; and a war between Mali and Niger.
  - March 25, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_346
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include the Pope's visit to Cuba, Mexico, and South America; the Senegalese elections and new president Macky Sall; the Tuareg rebellion in northern Mali; and the Toulouse and Montauban shootings in France.
  - April 2, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_347
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval. Discussed topics include the trial of former Guatemalan president Efraín Ríos Montt for crimes against humanity; the conviction of participants of the Guatemalan genocide against the Mayan indigenous peoples in 1982; the Syrian Civil War; the Tuareg rebellion in northern Mali and a coup d'état in southern Mali; and the large number of casulaties as a result of the Southern Libyan tribal clashes.
  - April 9, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_348
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Mahader Tesfai (Africa) and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the Bosnian War; Patriarch Kirill of Moscow and the Russian Orthodox Church; Russia trying to suppress gay rights; the hospitalization of Eritrean poet Yirgalem Fisseha Mebrahtu; the large number of detention camps in Eritrea with poor prison conditions; the Eritrean–Ethiopian War; fighting with Al-Shabaab in Somalia; and a Malian coup d'état and Tuareg rebellion in northern Mali.
  - April 16, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_349
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the UCSB Human Rights film series; the Chiong murder case in the Philippines; the impeachment trial of Renato Corona; the South China Sea dispute; the death of Ahmed Ben Bella and his legacy; and the chaotic Egyptian elections.
  - April 30, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_350
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Cedric Robinson and Lucy Edwards (Honduras). Discussed topics include President Charles Taylor being found guilty of war crimes and crimes against humanity; a counter coup attempt in Mali and the Tuareg rebellion; the Human Rights Accompaniment program in South America; and the history of Honduras, growing human rights violations, and the suppression of protests by police funded by Miguel Facussé.
  - May 14, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_351
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include the Libyan Civil War; Palestinian prisoners in Israel ending their hunger strike; the history of clandestine detention centers in Argentina and the Trelew massacre; the capture of Joseph Kony of the Lord's Resistance Army; and President Charles Taylor's defense counsel pleading that Taylor not be imprisoned in the U.K.
  - May 21, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_352
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the World Bank's Stolen Assets Recovery Initiative and political corruption globally; a Malian coup d'état and the Tuareg rebellion; the impeachment trial of Renato Corona; U.S. companies being allowed to invest in Myanmar; the democratic elections in Myanmar and Aung San Suu Kyi; and NATO meetings in Chicago and protests.
  - June 3, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_353
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Jovian Radheshwar (South Asia), Lucy Edwards (Honduras), and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include indigenous communities in Honduras protesting the construction of a dam; narco-traffic trade in Honduras; Padre Melo's activism; conflicts between campesinos and companies with extensive land; and left-wing extremism leading to attacks and land conflicts in India.
  - June 4, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_354
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Karzai family and the future of Afghanistan's government; growing racism in Israel against African refugees; the Yo Soy 132 movement in Mexico; the third anniversary of the 2009 Honduran coup d'état; the growing number of violent U.S. DEA drug raids in Honduras; the M23 rebellion in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and Bosco Ntaganda; and President Charles Taylor's trial and sentencing.
  - June 11, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_355
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guest was Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include combatants fighting in Northern Mali coming to an agreement; the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS); a Malian coup d'état; Malawi canceling the African Union summit because of tensions with President Omar al-Bashir; the Ocampo Four case; the death of South African anthropologist Phillip Tobias; the Yemeni revolution and increased rates of starvation in Yemen; global condemnation of Syria's actions during civil war; and growing tensions between Israel and Syria.
  - June 18, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_356
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Mahader Tesfai (Africa) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Israel trying to limit the number of African refugees; increased racism, deportations, and protests in Israel; the Egyptian elections and the election of Mohamed Morsi as president; the election of Fatou Bensouda as the new Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court; and the Gacaca courts in Rwanda holding their last legal cases.
  - June 25, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_357
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include a coup in Paraguay and the removal of President Fernando Lugo; the murder of Carlos Fuentealba in Argentina; President Barack Obama awarding the Medal of Freedom to Jan Karski, Gordon Hirabayashi, and Dolores Huerta; Madeline Albright and the Yugoslav Wars; and President Jimmy Carter's criticism of drone strikes.
  - July 2, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_358
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval. Discussed topics include the Mexican elections and politics; a parliamentary coup in Paraguay; the Egyptian elections and politics; human rights violations in Syria; the release of International Criminal Court agents after their arrest in Libya; and the destruction of historic sites in Mali by Ansar Dine.
  - July 23, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_359
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include the assassination of several Syrian government officials; the Assad regime and Syrian refugees; President François Hollande's acknowledgement of the Vichy regime's crimes amid rising racism and xenophobia in France; French nuclear testing linked to cancer cases and environmental damage; a mutiny by soldiers in Malagasy; and the U.S. State Department withdrawing military aid from Rwanda.
  - July 30, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_360
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Katia McClain and Hector Javkin. Discussed topics include Monsanto's investment into genetically-modified corn seed in Argentina; Estela de Carlotto and the Grandmothers of the Plaza de Mayo (Asociación Civil Abuelas de Plaza de Mayo); a bombing at Burgas Airport in Bulgaria; and Mitt Romney's tour of Europe and Israel.
  - August 6, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_361
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Cedric Robinson. Discussed topics include the defection of Syria's prime minister to Qatar; offshore financial centers and secrecy structures; a summit meeting to finalize the development of a police force to suppress the war between Rwanda and the Democratic Republic of the Congo; and French colonial history and its relation to the conflict in Mali.
  - August 13, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_362
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gary Colmenar. Discussed topics include the removal of Egyptian defense minister Hussein Tantawi and Armed Forces Chief of General Staff Sami Anan; the ongoing conflict in Syria; severe floods in the Philippines; the Daniel Hooper controversy at the Olympics and the defection of Olympic athletes; and the disintegration of the Malian state.
  - August 20, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_363
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include the Pussy Riot trial outcome in Russia; Vladimir Putin and Orthodox Church; the expulsion of Roma people from France; the miner strike and Marikana massacre in South Africa; and the activities of Shell Oil Company in Nigeria.
  - August 27, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_364
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Elizabeth Robinson and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include new information about Rachel Corrie's death in 2003 and other deaths at the hands of the Israeli Defense Force; the Syrian Civil War; the miner strike and the Marikana massacre in South Africa; the death of Prime Minister Meles Zanawi in Ethiopia; Togolese women calling for a sex strike; and the disintegration of the Malian state.
  - September 10, 2012, TW_TAM_835_ER_365